Alrighty, so we're going to talk through the sales script for the 21-day Kickstarter,
one block at a time. First up,
we've got building rapport and memory anchor.
Building a relationship with the client, and getting them to remember what
they spoke about with me. So,
the beginner browser, basic session, quick recap,
you get a booking, click up, it comes up,
and there's notes about the client, the discussion notes.
Of course, as a trainer, you're going to read through those notes,
so that you're prepared for the session,
and then you can tailor the session for whatever they want to achieve,
or for whatever level of advancement they're at.
The session happens, you fist bump them,
hey how's it going, etc.
You get into the first part of the workout, you do a set or
two. The first 5-10 minutes of the workout should be spent
just building rapport with them. Don't ask them anything related
to this. Ask them how the day was,
what did they do for work, what did you do on the weekend.
Not fake rapport, but just a little bit,
5-10 minutes max. After that,
within the rest periods, you'll want to start off with this.
So Jamie mentioned that you were interested in getting to goal.
This is the memory anchor.
This is a few benefits. The first thing,
it puts them in a really good buying position because they are being,
their memory is being anchored to when I spoke to them about their goals.
So you can skip that whole process essentially.
The second part is that it is
going to trigger their memory with some of the things we spoke about on
the call. So that they're once again going to give you better answers now.
And third of all, it shows them that we actually care about them and
that we don't just hand them off willy nilly without any discussion.
It shows that we actually take care their discussion notes and we pass
them on and that you've done your homework too.
So it makes them feel important as well. So it's really important you start
off with that memory anchor. So Jamie mentioned you were getting to,
you were interested in losing weight. Oh so Jamie,
Jamie told me you were wanting to ah build strength,
was that correct? Jamie told me you've never been to the gym before and
you just want to learn how to train. Jamie told me that you,
your GP told you you have to start training to reduce your cholesterol,
is that, is that right? Whatever.
So that's the first one. They'll say yep,
cool. And then you're going to follow that up with when was the last
time you were at goal? When was the last time
you were 50 kilos? When was the last time you were 5 kilos lighter?
When was the last time you were strong? When was the last time you
were consistent in the gym? When was the last time you were toned?
You mention this whenever they've been at that goal before.
Or,
if they've never been at that goal before, for example,
they've never, well they've always been lighter before,
they've never been stronger before,
or if they've never been to the gym before, or if they've never had
consistency before, how long have you been thinking about,
uh, building consistency in the gym? How long have you been thinking about building
strength? How long have you been thinking about building muscle?
Okay, so the first one is if they've been at that goal before,
which is more ideal, or the second one is if they've never been at
that goal before. Either or,
the per- purpose of it guys, is to do something called expand the gap.
From where they are now, to where they used to be.
And what this is going to do, is going to prevent an objection later,
which is, I need to think about it.
Because that- because I might have spoken to them over the phone, and they
said, I want to lose weight. And then you train them,
they're thinking that they've just decided then they want to lose weight.
So then they're not going to be ready to make a decision. But in
reality, they decided two years ago,
because they've been thinking about it for two years,
or they were at that weight two years ago. So it expands the gap
guys, and it gives us a bit more.
So you ask that question, you get an answer,
oh I've been thinking about it for six months,
for two years, for one year, for five years,
for ten plus years. You want them to say a number.
If they say yeah a few months, a few years,
get a number. How many? How many roughly?
You want a number. Next up,
and why do you need to make this change after X years?
We've expanded the gap, now we're getting them to vocalise why
they need to action on that gap now. Why do they want to do
that now? This is going to prevent that same objection,
I need to think about it. They can't say that if they're now saying
they need to make this change because it's been five years and they're sick
of feeling bad about themselves. So that is what that
question does. And it's also them soft-selling themselves into
doing the Kickstarter later.
I've been wanting to lose weight for four years and I need,
why did I make this change John? Because I just,
my GP said I need to lose weight, I'm struggling to get up the
stairs every day, I don't feel good about myself. That's the green brain stuff,
that's the gold. Those are the emotions,
the emotional buying motivators.
That brings them towards signing up,
okay. So if they don't, if they give you a basic answer,
oh because you know I want to lose weight, say,
but why, why do you want to lose weight?
To look better, okay, then why do you want to look better?
So that I can be around for my kids every day.
You want to dig deep,
dive deep into that. So that's the script word
for word, guys when it comes to scripts,
there's two ways to go about it, you can either memorise it word for
word, or you can put your own spin on it.
I recommend at a bare minimum learning the script word for word,
because the more you know the script, the less you're going to focus on
trying to remember the script, and the more you can focus on personalising the
script. So instead of being,
so Jamie mentioned you were trying to lose weight,
you can be like, so Jamie mentioned you were interested in losing weight.
Okay, so learning the script doesn't make you robotic,
it actually makes you better at it. But,
regardless, I also give you a breakdown of the script.
These are the things you need to tick off,
no matter what you say. First you need to reference my discussion with
them and their goal. Next you need to ask about the history with the
goal, a.k.a. how long has it been.
And next you need to understand why they need to make the change now.
Why now? Why did they accept that free session now?
Why did they sign up to the gym recently?
Why do they need to do it now? This establishes trust and all of
this shows that you need to remember their journey from my discussion with you
and that you really care about them as an individual.